const e={sections:[{header:{text:"Transform the sentences into indirect speech."},exercises:[{type:"test",question:'Dinara said: "Marat, do your homework very quickly."',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Dinara asked Marat to do his homework very quickly.",2:"Dinara asked Marat did his homework very quickly.",3:"Dinara asked Marat to does his homework very quickly."}},{type:"test",question:`"Don't move!" the police officer said.`,rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The police officer ordered not to move.",2:"The police officer ordered to don't move.",3:"The police officer ordered to not move."}},{type:"test",question:'"Please, wait for me!" she said to Marat.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"She asked Marat to wait for her.",2:"She asked Marat not to wait for her.",3:"She asked Marat to waited for her."}},{type:"test",question:'"Shall we go to the library?" Vanya said to Dinara.',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"Vanya offered Dinara to go to the library.",2:"Vanya offered Dinara to shall go to the library.",3:"Vanya offered Dinara go to the library."}},{type:"test",question:`"Don't touch my money," the bank manager said.`,rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:"The bank manager asked not to touch his money.",2:"The bank manager asked to not touch his money.",3:"The bank manager asked don't touch his money."}}]},{header:{text:"Translate into English using indirect commands"},exercises:[{type:"test",question:"Динара попросила брата отнести письмо на почту.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:'Dinara said, "Brother, bring this letter to the post-office, please"',2:'Dinara said, "Bring this letter to the post-office!"',3:'Dinara said, "Brother, brought this letter to the post-office, please"'}},{type:"test",question:"Учительница говорит ученикам выучить стихотворение наизусть.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:'The teacher says, "Learn that poem by heart"',2:'The teacher said, "To learn that poem by heart"',3:'The teacher says, "To learn that poem by heart"'}},{type:"test",question:"Я пригласила друзей в кино.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:`"Let's go to the cinema?"`,2:`"Let's went to the cinema?"`,3:'"I invite my friend to the cinema"',4:"Учитель попросил перевести два текста до вторника."}},{type:"test",question:'a) The teacher said, "To translate two texts until Tuesday"',rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:'The teacher said, "Translate two texts until Tuesday"',2:"The teacher asked the students to translate two texts until Tuesday."}},{type:"test",question:"Доктор прописал пациенту долгие прогулки на свежем воздухе.",rightAnswerIds:["1"],answers:{1:'The doctor said to the patient, "Take long walks in the fresh air, please"',2:'The doctor prescribed to the patient, "Walk in the fresh air"',3:'The doctor said to the patient, "Took long walks in the fresh air, please"'}}]}]};export{e as default};
